

SENIOR DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER · FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Pune. Maharashtra. India

□ (+91) 9975258323 | waibhavbhavsar62@gmail.com | waibhav6233m.github.io | waibhav6233m | waibhav-bhavsar | waibhav-bhavsar-000bh276

Summary

Software Engineer with around **6 years** experience specializing in backend, frontend UI, and Cross-platform desktop application development. Possess comprehensive knowledge of **JavaScript** with solid understanding of asynchronous programming. Super nerd who enjoys to customize the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Technical Proficiency _____

Programming Languages JavaScript, Node.JS, Python

Web Technologies ReactJs, VueJs, Microsoft FluentUI, MaterialUI, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks ElectronJs, ExpressJs

Databases MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Servers Apache2, Nginx, IIS

Version Control Git

Operating Systems Windows, Linux, Mac

Cloud Tech's Azure DevOps, AWS, Google Firebase, Docker Containerization, Travis CI

Work Experience _____

MSCI INC.

Pune, India

ASSOCIATE Oct. 2020 - PRESENT

- Development of frontend applications using React.js framework around the finance domain in collaboration with Microsoft.
- Producing clean, efficient code based on specifications
- Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Integrate software components and third-party programs
- Recommend improvements to existing software programs as necessary

CALSOFT INC. Pune, India

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

• Developing frontend applications using **Vue.js** framework as per client's requirements

- Producing clean, efficient code based on specifications
- Integrate software components and third-party programs
- Estimated work hours and tracked progress using **Scrum** methodology.
- · Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies

WINJIT TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD. SOFTWARE ENGINEER & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Nashik, India

Dec. 2017 - Jun. 2019

July. 2019 - Sep. 2020

- Code, test and operate JavaScript/Python based services
- Build customer-facing UI and back-end services in NodeJs and Python
- Define code architecture decisions to support a high-performance and scalable product
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade existing software
- · Optimize applications for maximum speed and scalability
- Responsible for the dealing with problems, defect, fixing and troubleshooting

SUPER SIMPLE SOFTWARE LLP.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashik, India

Aug. 2015 - Nov. 2017

• Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications

• Develop and implement new **ERP software** programs in **Python/XML** based framework

- Testing and deploying programs and systems
- Work with developers to design algorithms and flowcharts
- Maintain and improve the performance of existing software
- Collaborate well with engineers to design and create advanced, elegant and efficient systems

Vaibhav A. Bhavsar · Résumé

Projects Handled

MSCI: ESG Manager: ClimateRisk Lab

msci.com

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Duration: Ongoing project

- · Team Size: 15+
- **Description:** ESG Manager (ESGM) is a client-only portal where you can access all MSCI ESG Research products including ESG ClimateRisk, ESG Ratings, ESG Controversies, etc. **ClimateRisk Lab** is designed to provide corporate and institutional investors transparency into a company's climate-related risks and opportunities, in accordance with the recommendations from the Task Force on Climate related Financial Disclosures (TCFD).
- · Responsibilities:
 - Understanding the business requirements and developing customer-facing UI **ReactJs** Framework.
 - Integration of PowerBI reports to visualize Climate Risk and business related data.
 - Development and consumption of NodeJs APIs with ExpressJs.
 - Implementing reusable UI-components with Microsoft Fluent-UI.

Seagate: Cloud Storage Manager

seagate.com

Duration: 10 Months

- Full Stack Developer

 Team Size: 13+
- Description: Cloud Storage Manager (CSM) is a virtualization layer that provides functionality to configure and provision storage, manage users, set policies and provide statistics.
- · Responsibilities:
 - Understanding the business requirements and developing customer-facing UI **VueJs** Framework.
 - Development and consumption of **NodeJs** APIs with **ExpressJs**.
 - Implementing reusable UI-components as per **UI-styleguide**.
 - Developed overall application with **ES6** standards for better usages of javascript modules.

BuildingLink: Online Residential Property Management Software

buildinglink.com

Duration: 4 Months

- FRONT-END DEVELOPER

 Team Size: 4
- Description: BuildingLink.com is a property management software developed to help property managers handle their operations better.
- · Responsibilities:
 - Understanding the business requirements and developing customer-facing UI **VueJs** Framework.
 - Implemented reusable UI-components with **Material-UI** for BuildingLink web application.
 - Interaction with development teams to integrate code.

lagon: Decentralized and Secure Cloud Platform

iagon.com

Duration: 12 Months

- Full Stack Developer

 Team Size: 5
- **Description:** IAGON is an Open Source platform for harnessing the storage capacities and processing power of multiple computers over a decentralized Blockchain grid.
- Responsibilities:
 - Lead in the development and implementation of distributed storage using BitTorrent technology and processing functionality using IPFS (Distributed Web) and Docker containers in lagon Cloud Services.
 - Implementation and Integration of Iagon Cloud Services in a Cross-platform desktop application using ElectronJs and ReactJs.
 - Developed Peer-2-Peer communication system to achieve decentralize processing functionality.
 - Development and consumption of NodeJs APIs with ExpressJs.
 - Integrated an HTTP tunneling service to resolve the node communication issues of NAT/Firewall.

Education

SINHGAD COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING

Pune, India

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

May. 2011 - Jun. 2015

• Score: 62.60%

Honors & Awards

20191st Place, Technical Treasure HuntCalsoft Inc.2018Key Contributor, World of Winjit (WOW)Winjit Tech.2018Best Project - IAGON, World of Winjit (WOW)Winjit Tech.

Miscellaneous_

LANGUAGES:

• English: Business Fluent

• German: Beginner